yrdsb.ca 2019-05-28

# Pages - Legal Statements

The York Region District School Board is committed to open communication with our site visitors - be they students, parents, staff or visitors from the York Region community or beyond. 

The YRDSB Information Access and Privacy Office is accountable for the YRDSB’s policies and practices with respect to the management of all information including personal information. The YRDSB is committed to collecting, using and disclosing information responsibly and only to the extent necessary for the services and programs we provide. We also try to be open and transparent as to how we manage information. Direct complaints and inquiries about records and information management practices to the Information Access and Privacy Office: 

> In accordance with Policy #158.00 Information Access and Privacy all personal information in the custody or control of the York Region District School Board is treated as confidential and in accordance with relevant legislation and regulations.​

Personal information is any information that renders an individual identifiable. This includes images, name, age, date of birth, address, and health information. Personal information does not include business information (business title, work location, email address). 

All information in the custody and control of the YRDSB is retained according to the Official Retention Schedule. To ensure personal information is unrecoverable, a utility program is used to remove the electronic data and any paper records are shredded.

This privacy statement is applicable to all YRDSB websites. 

YRDSB respects the privacy of its internet users and will protect that privacy to the extent possible. 

YRDSB does not automatically gather any information that readily identifies you. This information is only obtained if you volunteer to provide it. If you do choose to provide us with your identifying personal information, it will be used to respond to your message and to help us get you the information or service you have requested. For example, if you are ordering an Ontario Student Transcript, your personal information is needed to process your order. YRDSB undertakes that such information will be kept strictly confidential. 

When your personal information is collected there will be a notice outlining our legal authority to collect and use your information, how we will use it and information allowing you to contact someone if you have questions about the collection and use. 

Individual information provided to the YRDSB will not be sold or made available to a third party. We are not responsible for any access or content of web sites linked to the YRDSB web site. 

YRDSB reserves the right to collect information for traffic monitoring and for statistics keeping. The information is analyzed for operational trends, performance, and for ways to improve the site. Only aggregated data, not individual personal information, will be used for this purpose. 

We have attempted to ensure that the information contained on this site is accurate, relevant and up-to-date. We cannot, however, assume responsibility should errors or omissions occur. For more general inquiries about information access and privacy protection in the Ontario Public Sector, please visit the website of the Freedom of [Information and Privacy Commission of Ontario​](http://www.ipc.on.ca/).

The contents of this site may be viewed, downloaded, or printed for personal, non-commercial use only. **The contents of all materials on this site are the property of YRDSB and/or its employees. Distribution or commercial use without permission is strictly prohibited.**

**The name York Region District School Board, YRDSB, the logo of York Region District School Board, as well as the related names and graphics are trademarks and the property of York Region District School Board; they are not in the public domain and may not be duplicated or used without permission. Commercial use is strictly prohibited.  **

We are committed to providing accessibility to everyone, including individuals with disabilities as consistent with the four core principles of the Accessibility for Ontarians with Disability Act (AODA): Independence, Dignity, Integration, and Equality of Opportunity. Building fully accessible learning and working environments requires shared responsibilities and collaboration across the Board, and this is reflected in our Accessibility Policy. This policy and its related procedures formally outline our commitment to accessibility and provide a framework for how we are building accessible learning and working communities for all YRDSB students, staff, visitors and customers. For additional information, please visit our Accessibility website.
